

Experience

Senior Developer/UX Engineer/IA

re:group Integrated Marketing 2013 - Present

- Collect insights by creating user surveys, leading user testing, and facilitating A/B testing
- Incorporate user data into UI designs
- Generate content outlines, site maps, and interactive wireframes
- · Collaborate with clients to ensure that the delivered product meets expectations

Design Victory

• In 2015, I completed a website redesign for a Michigan medical practice. With the previous design, only 30% of users were able to successfully use the "Find a Doctor" tool. On the new site, over 80% of users find the correct doctor or facility.

Lead Developer/UX Designer

Stone Interactive Group 2010 - 2013

- Managed four to six development projects at a time, while handling support tickets
- Maintained live sites by updating UI elements and developing user testing for continued growth of the site
- Worked up from support manager to lead developer through proven proficiency in emerging web technologies
- Leveraged my experience in support for insights into common user issues

Graphic Designer/Front End Developer

Ferris State Admissions Office 2008 - 2010

- Helped to grow the marketing-focused web department from one to a team of five, including four developers and one videographer
- Maintained the marketing website for prospective students
- Maintained brand standards

Graphic Design Intern

Ferris State Design Project Center 2009 - 2010

- Worked with a team of other students to produce a website, brochure, fliers, and buttons for the school's Good Choices campaign
- Met with the client and presented the campaign to a committee board in order to approve a budget for printing
- Collaborated with a television production team to design and produce a video for the website's homepage

About

As a child, I wanted to be a jet plane (not a pilot), or maybe a robotic dinosaur. These days, I'm happy to be a web maker, although I haven't given up the dream of someday being a robot. I love spending my days transforming the web into a friendlier and less frustrating place through user-focused design. To me, this means basing design decisions on research and data to provide users with what they need, when they need it. Sarah Parmenter, Luke Wroblewski, and Jeffrey Zeldman are some of my UX design idols.

Recently, I've been working with a professor from my alma mater to better integrate web development practices and processes into the design curriculum. I think it's critical that new design graduates are familiar with web technologies.

When I'm not making things on the web, I like to make things at home: cooking, dis/re-assembling my bikes, or honing my amateur luthier skills. Once I'm worn out, you'll often find me lounging with my two dogs (Princess Zelda and Sir Ralph Ralphington III, Esquire) and watching old horror films or re-watching Stargate for the tenth time

Education

Bachelor of Science in Graphic Design Ferris State University Winter 2005 - Spring 2010

Skills

Proficient in Mac & PC **Browser Optimization JSON**

Angular PHP

MySQL

Playing guitar

Javascript

Jquery

Velocity

CodeIgniter

HTML5

CSS SASS

LESS

Grunt

Bower

Gulp

Joomla

Drupal

Magento

Wordpress

CLI

UX

IΑ

Node

Yeoman

JSlint Sketch

Photoshop

InDesign Illustrator

Cycling

Luthier

User Testing

A/B Testing